So I want to leave the realm of Route parameters and so on soon.
Bu yzden, Rota parametrelerinin alann terk etmek istiyorum.
One more thing I want to do though, we have that home link which is not marked as active when being
Yapmak istediim bir ey daha var; bu nedenle, tek bir yayndayken etkin olarak
on a single post and it kind of makes sense by the label of it.
iaretlenmeyen ve etiketiyle mantkl grnen homoyumlar eklemeliyiz.
But what if this was named posts which would make sense because we have a lot of posts there
Ama eer bu, mantkl olacak olan mesajlar olarak adlandrlmsa, orada ok sayda mesajmz var.
so let's maybe rename that link to be posts.
Bu yzden belki bu linki mesajlar olarak yeniden adlandralm.
If we do this, now it will be strange that it's not highlighted when we are on a single post,
Bunu imdi yaparsak, tek bir yazdayken vurgulanmam olmas garip olur.
we certainly would want this. Now the reason for this of course is exact, since exact is set, this only is
Kesinlikle isteyeyim elbette exect iin bir sebep deil exect ayarlandndan bu sadece aktif
treated as active if we well have exactly this
olarak kabul edilir nk tam olarak bunu.
URL is just slash and not slash three which we have of course for the post with ID.
L konumundasn ve eik izgi izmeyelim, tabiki kimliimizle olan elbette elimizde olan elimizden kurtulmuyorsun.
The problem is that if we remove exact what we saw that before, now it will be marked as active for
Sorun u ki, daha nce grdmz eyleri tek bir yayn iin etkin olarak iaretleyeceiz,
a single post but also for a new post.
ancak yeni bir yayn iin de etkin olarak iaretlenecektir.
So this is kind of tricky and it's only really tricky for this exact case that we're talking about,
Dolaysyla bu biraz zor ve bu bahsettiimiz kesin durum iin gerekten zor, sadece kendin
the root URL.
olduunu kk yapyorsan l.
If we had /posts then it will be a different story and we could absolutely use this prefix because
E-postalar kesilmi halde farkl bir hikaye olacak ve kesinlikle bu neki
we probably have no conflicts with our routes in the application.
kullanabiliriz nk muhtemelen uygulamadaki rotalarmzla eliki grmyoruz.
It's really just that root URL, this root path of just slash which happens to be part of any page
ya da baka bir ey de, bu uygulamann herhangi bir sayfasnn bir paras haline gelen sadece eik izginin kaba POV'si.
in our app.
Gerekten sadece kaba
So this is just an edge case here, a special case and I'm going to add exact again
Bu yzden burada sadece zel bir durum olan bir durum daha var ve tekrar tam olarak ekleyeceim.
therefore not getting highlighting for a single post.
Bu nedenle, tek bir yaz iin vurgulamyor.
And again it is fine for me because this is an edge case which you will rarely face.
Ve yine benim iin sorun yok nk bu nadiren karlaacanz ek bir vaka.
Most of the time your posts are going to be at slash posts and I'm just not changing it here to deliberately
ou zaman yaynlarnzn eik yazlarda olaca sylenir ve burada bu davay referans
leave this edge case here for reference.
amacyla brakmak iin burada deitirmemekteyim.
I just wanted to bring this to your awareness,
Bunu sadece farkndalnza getirmek istedim.
you can face issues when using the root path,
Kk POV'yi kullanrken sorunlarla karlaabilirsiniz.
Just slash and you want to style some child components but not all of them,
Sadece eik izgi ve baz chawl bileenleri stil istiyorum ama hepsini deil.
so some paths which follow it but not all paths,
Yani takip eden baz blmler, ancak tm POS deil.
this is really tricky to do,
Gerekten yapmak zor.
not really possible.
Gerekten mmkn deil.
You typically use more specific routes like /posts though so this shouldn't be an issue.
Genelde Slash postalar gibi daha spesifik rotalar kullanyorsunuz, bu yzden bu bir sorun olmamal.